Vinay Chowdary Katta

255 W 2F 31st street Chicago, IL 60616 • Tel: (630) 853-6380 • vinaykatta89@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Around 10 + years of extensive Development and Support experience in the field of Information Technology. Developed applications using ServiceNow platform and experience in Java, Jakarta EE, JPA, JSF, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, and React JS. Ability to prioritize; manage work, take decisions and work in tandem with different departments ensuring on time delivery.

EDUCATION

ILLINOIS INSTITUE OF TECHNOLOGY, CHICAGO.

Expected Graduation Date: Dec 2023

Master's Information technology and Management

Major in Software Development

KL University, India Graduation Date: April 2011

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science and Technology

SKILLS

Languages: Java, SQL, Spring MVC, JDBC, JPA (Java Persistence API), JSP, JSF, Selenium and Data Structures

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, React

Frameworks: Express, Pug

Opensource Tools: Apache POI, Maven, GIT, Jenkins, VS Code, Eclipse

Cloud: Microsoft azure, Google Cloud

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, My SQL, better-sqlite3, MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer

December 2017 - August 2022

SERVICENOW

Hyderabad, India

- Development of Forms, Fields, Workflows, UI Pages for ITSM products.
- Released many versions of Store Apps like Site Reliability Operations and Site Reliability Metrics using ServiceNow platform capabilities.
- Worked on Slack and Zoom integration for Change and Incident Management products.
- Machine learning solutions for IT Service Management products like Incident, Problem and Change Management
- Development of Scripts using ATF which helps customer seamless upgrade to latest release
- Conducting boot camp sessions for new joiners and technical support teams
- Demoing product new features to customer and help them in implementations and smoother upgrade process
- Participate in on-call rotation resolving critical issues or outages during off work hours and weekends.
- Unit Testing, Automation of every feature to find out bugs in early stage of development
- Resolve Case tasks created by customers for different ITSM Products

Technologies: ServiceNow Platform, Workflow automation, Java, JavaScript, CSS, Node.js, Git-hub.

Senior Software Engineer

July 2015 - December 2017

INNOMINDS SOFTWARE PVT. LTD Worked for CA Technologies at Client location

Hyderabad, India

- Worked on designing and implementing Data catalog web application.
- Developed microservices using spring boot and swagger to expose APIs to API gateway.
- Designed and implemented search algorithm using Azure cognitive search. All search requests hit the search algorithm to get appropriate results handled in microservice architecture.
- Written multiple batch jobs on spring boot that run every night.
- Took part in Java version upgrade for almost every project successfully.
- Written various automated processes and unit test cases to decrease manual work for a quality analyst.

Technologies: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, Azure, Git-hub.

Software Engineer

March 2011 - November 2014

SS&C Technologies (formerly DST Systems, Inc.)

Hyderabad India

- Involved in design, development of the workflow, process models, custom stored procedures
- Developed the algorithm to provide the automated matching functionality based on the 837 fields
- Design and development of configuration screen and the user matching screen and DAO classes to retrieve the data.
- Published WSDL SOAP service which retrieves address information based on requestor type

- Developed a communications module, an automation service which sends out a correspondence letter
- Documentation of the installing instructions and deploying the solution onto Dev and Quality environments

Technologies: Java, J2EE, JSP, Spring Batch, Spring MVC, WebSphere MQ, HTML, Java Script, CSS, HTML5, GIT, Jenkins, Junit, IBM DB2 and JIRA.

ACHIEVEMENTS AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Recognized with LLAMA Award for Q1 2021 for my outstanding contributions to SRM store release and customer interactions.
- Member of GivingAtNow and volunteered various CSR activities.